planetminecraft.com 2018-12-24

# Privacy Policy - Planet Minecraft

Your Privacy Rights - Effective May 25, 2018

## Introduction

We want you to understand how and why Planet Minecraft (“PMC”, “ we” or “us”) collects, uses and shares information about you when you access and use the Planet Minecraft website and Services.

## Information Collected

We collect the minimum amount of data to adequately provide our Services while preventing the abuse of our Services, members & visitors.

### Visitors

We log visitor IPs to prevent artificially inflating content stats, views, and to help prevent repeat malicious or inappropriate activities. View logs are flushed / deleted within 90 days.

### Members

We require minimal information, a username (not your real name) and an email address for signing up with the purpose of activating your account and notification of important events related to your Account or our Services ( news, policy changes, etc ). We do not share your email address publicly on PMC or with third parties.

We automatically log your member IP to prevent the abuse of our Services. Your actual IP is not displayed anywhere including in our moderation tools. Only Admin can view your real IP.

A username is used for public display and recognition on our Services. We discourage the use of a real name and if you are located in the EEA, it is a violation of this privacy policy to reveal your identity in your username.

We also use such data to enable us to comply with copyright law, with 18 USC §2258A (illegal content), and to respond to lawful requests by public authorities, including national security, courts, and law enforcement.

### Content and Information you choose to submit

We collect content and other information you choose to provide to us when using our Services. Examples include posting submissions, comments, forum topics & replies, profile pages, voting, social media links, etc. These optional activities are kept in a database in order to keep track of the intended actions made with our Services and provide the intentional outcome of sharing content with the community, affecting vote scores, subscribing to members, sending messages to other members, promoting your social media profiles, etc.

## Control, Rights & Correction of your Data

As a member, you have control to rectify or remove what you post as well as change your username and email at anytime. If you are unable to access your account, you can request the specific modification or complete removal of your content or account via our contact form or ticket system. Please be aware that the public posts, messages, and activities you submitted prior to deleting your account will remain visible to others, unless you remove or request removal of such content.

We may retain internal information as required by law or for protecting against Service, member or visitor abuse.

If you have questions or need help correcting or removing your data, contact us.

## Information about children

We don’t believe social media is suitable for children under 13 years of age and therefore all members must confirm they are of 13 years or older when signing up. To comply with GDPR, we raised the age confirmation to 16 for EU members on sign up. Individuals under the age of 13, 16 in EU, may not create an account or otherwise access or use the Services.

## Data Protection & Security

We take every reasonable precaution to protect the data on our servers from loss, misuse, unauthorized access, disclosure, alteration, or destruction, taking into account the risk level and the nature of the data. You are responsible for taking every reasonable precaution on your end to protect any unauthorized person from accessing your Planet Minecraft account. We recommend using complex and unique passwords for all of your online accounts.

## Ads and Analytics Partners

We may partner with third-party advertisers, ad networks, and analytic providers to deliver advertising and content that is targeted to your interests or to better understand your use of the Services. These third parties may collect information sent by your computer, browser, or mobile device in response to a request for content, such as unique identifiers, your IP address, or other information about your computer or device. If you would like more information about this practice and to know your choices about not having this information used by these companies visit: [networkadvertising.org](https://www.networkadvertising.org/ "Network Advertising").

We do not provide our partners with links to your account or access to your Planet Minecraft account information.

We use analytics partners, such as Google Analytics, to help analyze usage and traffic for our Services.

## Changes to this Privacy Policy

We may revise this privacy policy from time to time to provide greater clarity, abid with the changing online legal landscape or after significant updates to our Services. You can determine the date of the most recent changes by looking at the “effective date” at the top.

## Contact Us

If you have any questions about this Privacy Policy, please contact us.
